RUBEN A. SANCHEZ

\bigcirc	ruasanch@ucsc.edu
~	Tuasamun wucst.cuu

rubenasanchez.com

in rubenasanchez

EDUCATION

2015 B.A. Linguistics University of California, Santa Cruz 2015 B.S. Cognitive Science University of California, Santa Cruz

PUBLICATION

Zyzik, E.C., & Sanchez, R.A. (2019). Beyond accuracy: Heritage speakers' performance on two kinds of acceptability judgement tasks. *Applied Psycholinguistics*, 40(3), 645-671. http://doi.org/10.1017/S0142716418000760

RESEARCH EXPERIENCE

2017 to 2018 Data Analyst - Bilingualism Research Lab University of California, Santa Cruz Responsible for conducting data pre-processing, coding, quality control, exploratory analysis, inferential analysis, data visualizations, and completing written reports.

2016 Annotator - Natural Language & Dialogue Systems University of California, Santa Cruz Annotated social media content for computational modeling via language entrainment and narrative summarizations.

2013 to 2014 Research Assistant - Cognitive Science Department University of California, Santa Cruz Coded acoustic data with Praat and video data with After Effects for a linguistic phonetic study.

2012 Research Assistant - Linguistics Department University of California, Santa Cruz Developed, implemented, and completed a phonological study. Designed and prepared stimuli, scheduled and ran participants, as well as analyzed and reported data.

TEACHING EXPERIENCE

2020 Academic Success Mentor

Served as advisor for student at risk of loosing residency due to failed coursework.

- Guided student through studying best practices.
- Developed a strategy plan for completing assignments.
- Advised on stress coping mechanisms and directed to resources.
- Student successfully completed the quarter and graduated.

2018 to 2019 Private Tutor

Tutored college students in mathematics.

2018 to 2019 Volunteer Tutor

Tutored international students in English composition.

SUMMARY OF QUALIFICATIONS

Expertise Cognitive research, neurolinguistics, phonetic psycholinguistics, data visualization,

web development, illustration, and 2D animation.

Research Interested in investigating the neural circuitry responsible for the assignment of semantic

Interests coding onto phonetic units perceived as linguistically relevant.

Also interested in multimodal communicative strategies for human computer interaction.

Programming Python, R, SQL, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, GIT, LATEX, markdown Research E-Prime, Superlab, Praat, Audacity, ELAN, SPSS, Mendeley, Zotero

Design Photoshop, Illustrator, After Effects, Figma, Invision, Blender

Leadership Project Management, Team Building, Issue Resolution

Languages English, Italian, Japanese, Spanish

CURRENT PROJECTS

2020 Web Based Interactive 3D Brain Model

Teaching myself advanced 3D modeling methods for developing an interactive model of the human brain which displays areas currently known to be pertinent to the perception and production of sounds relevant to language.